Salvatore Bevilacqua

26 Reginald Street, D8, Dublin 087 1604950 salvo.bevi@gmail.com

PROFILE

I am a positive and enthusiastic person with good interpersonal skills and hard- working attitude. Furthermore, during my previous experiences, I got good problem-solving skills and analytical thinking. I enjoy and am capable of both working on my own initiative or as part of a team. Able to work accurately under pressure and confident in a multicultural environment.

LANGUAGES

Italian (Mother tongue) English French

EDUCATION

07/01/2020-Present

Code Institute - Currently studying for a Diploma in Software Development at Code Institute. Skills acquired till now in Programming, Languages & Tools: HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3, Git, GitHub, Bootstrap

02/10/2015-09/06/2016

Preliminary English Test (PET)Cambridge English - Language Assessment in Edward Lear, Siderno (Italy)

2004-2010 Diploma

"Zaleuco" (scientific high school), Locri (Italy)Courses studies included: Italian language and literature; history and civics; philosophy; English and French languages; mathematics, physics, chemistry and natural sciences.

WORK EXPERIENCE 19/03/2019 - 01/05/2020

Customer Support Representative Cook Medical EMEA

- Place or cancel orders;
- Arrange product returns, refunds and replacements;
- Provide accurate valid and complete information via phone/email;
- Handle complaints, provide appropriate solutions and alternatives and follow up to ensure resolution;
- Communicate and coordinate with internal departments
- Follow communication procedures, guidelines and policies

- Completes supporting paperwork and data entry as required
- Keep records of customer interactions and internal queries;
- Provide accurate, valid and complete information by using the right methods/tools

01/06/2018 - 28/02/2019

Enterprise Credit Controller UPS

- Responsible for the timely collection of all outstanding debts.
- Maintaining the ledger and collecting debts in a timely manner whilst controlling Aged debts.
- Controlling unapplied cash items by means of reconciliation
- Ensuring that disputed items are reviewed and necessary action taken to resolve accordingly.
- Working closely with EAM (Enterprise Account Manager) to ensure proactive steps are taken when issues are discovered.
- Developing and sustaining an excellent rapport with customer.
- Actively working to reduce the total outstanding amount of invoices which have aged beyond agreed payment terms
- Running weekly conference calls with finance team and Account Payable to discuss aged invoices and open issues.
- Providing a high level of customer service, as main billing point of contact for UPS.

06/02/2017 - 31/05/2018

Billing Customer Service Representative UPS

Interact with customers to provide and process information in response to inquiries, concerns and requests about billing issues.

Responsible for ensuring that customer inquiries are resolved at the first point of contact, unless specialist knowledge or further information is required. Doing this by using judgement and taking decisions within established procedures for each inquiry.

- Answers incoming customer calls regarding billing issues: oversee and adjust billing issues
- Investigating and solving promptly customers' inquiries
- Manage large amounts of incoming calls
- Resolve customer inquiries via phone and email
- Identify and assess customers' needs to achieve satisfaction
- Build sustainable relationships of trust through open and interactive communication
- Provide accurate, valid and complete information by using the right methods/tools
- Provide appropriate solutions and alternatives within the time limits; follow up to ensure resolution
- Communicate and coordinate with internal departments
- Follow communication procedures, guidelines and policies
- Completes supporting paperwork and data entry as required
- Escalate calls to relevant departments when required
- FIF files large calculation file
- Manage mail inbox for a Preferred Customer: personalized communications and resolution of billing issues

11/06/2016-05/06/2017

Bartender Enoteca Italiana Ltd/A Dunne & Crescenzi Dublin, Éire/Ireland

- Responsible of the till and the payments.
- Checking all the deliveries.
- Giving advice and guidance on product selection to customers.
- Dealing with customer issues and complains (Monitoring customer satisfaction and problem solving).
- Taking reservations by phone.
- Extensive knowledge of the menu in order to be able to answer question about menu items and make recommendations.
- Making coffee.

09/01/2015-17/07/2015

Operator of the kennel Rifugio del Cane e del Gatto - Canile e Gattile Comunale di Bologna, Bologna (Italy)

- Provided daily walks, play times, baths, basic grooming, as well as professional dog obedience training.
- Cleaned and sanitized dog yards, cages and service areas.
- Moved the animals to selected locations around the shelter.
- Socialized the animals in order for them to become adoptable.
- Provided medical care, distributing medication, wound wraps, and transports to vet.
- Recorded and reported daily observations related to health and behaviour.
- Administered oral vaccinations.
- Learned additional responsibilities as assigned.

03/12/2013-02/12/2014

Private - VFP1Italian Army - Ministry of Defence, Remanzacco (Italy)

Voluntary for a year at the Italian army. Discharged final evaluation: Excellent.8° Reggimento Trasporti. Ufficio Maggiorità e Personale, Nucleo Militari di Truppa, Viale Del Sole, 105-33047 Remanzacco (UD).